{
    "QandAList": [
        {
            "category": ".NET",
            "topic_id": "14",
            "question": "What is the namespace in which .NET has the data functionality classes ?",
            "answer": "System.data, System.Data.OleDB, System.Data.SqlClient, System.XML"
        },
        {
            "category": ".NET",
            "topic_id": "14",
            "question": "An overview of ADO.NET architecture",
            "answer": "The most important section in ADO.NET architecture is 'Data Provider'.Data Provider provides access to datasource (SQL SERVER , ACCESS ,ORACLE).In short it provides object to achieve functionalities like opening and closing connection , retrieve data and update data."
        },
        {
            "category": ".NET",
            "topic_id": "14",
            "question": "What are the two fundamental objects in ADO.NET ?",
            "answer": "Datareader and Dataset"
        },
        {
            "category": ".NET",
            "topic_id": "14",
            "question": "What is the use of connection object ?",
            "answer": "They are used to connect a data to a Command object.An OleDbConnection object is used with an OLE-DB provider.A SqlConnection object uses Tabular Data Services (TDS) with MS SQL Server."
        },
        {
            "category": ".NET",
            "topic_id": "14",
            "question": "What is Dataset object?",
            "answer": "The DataSet provides the basis for disconnected storage and manipulation of relational data. We fill it from a data store,work with it while disconnected from that data store, then reconnect and flush changes back to the data store if required."
        },
        {
            "category": ".NET",
            "topic_id": "14",
            "question": "How can we save all data from dataset ?",
            "answer": "Dataset has 'AcceptChanges' method which commits all the changes since last time 'Acceptchanges' has been executed."
        },
        {
            "category": ".NET",
            "topic_id": "14",
            "question": "How can we check that some changes have been made to dataset since it was loaded ?",
            "answer": "Dataset has two methods which comes as rescue 'GetChanges' and 'HasChanges'."
        },
        {
            "category": ".NET",
            "topic_id": "14",
            "question": "What's the basic use of 'DataView' ?",
            "answer": "'DataView' represent's a complete table or can be small section of row's depending on some criteria.It's best used for sorting and finding data with in 'datatable'."
        },
        {
            "category": ".NET",
            "topic_id": "14",
            "question": "Why is DataSet slower than DataReader ?",
            "answer": "Biggest drawbacks of DataSet is speed.As 'DataSet' carry considerable overhead because of relations,multiple tables etc speed is slower than 'DataReader'.Always try to use 'DataReader' where ever possible , as it's meant specially for speed performance."
        },
        {
            "category": ".NET",
            "topic_id": "14",
            "question": "What's difference between 'Optimistic' and 'Pessimistic' locking ?",
            "answer": "In pessimistic locking when user wants to update data it locks the record and till then no one can update data.Other user's can only view the data when there is pessimistic locking. In optimistic locking multiple user's can open the same record for updating , thus increase maximum concurrency.Record is only locked when updating the record.This is the most preferred way of locking practically."
        }
    ]
}